<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Culture | zeyus dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/categories/culture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-26T13:46:38+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.zeyus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[zeyus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sick of It All]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2013/11/28/sick-of-it-all/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-28T03:14:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2013/11/28/sick-of-it-all</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/W-7m8fnfLTk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>So, I originally started this post planning to cover various topics, but I think I&rsquo;ll tackle them one at a time&hellip;there&rsquo;s too much to cover and some research involved.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve just got so upset with the amount of bad content that I see constantly posted and reposted on Facebook or elsewhere, it&rsquo;s frustrating, it&rsquo;s saddening, and it shows a general lack of interest in thinking. It doesn&rsquo;t take long to visit a few websites such as <a href="http://www.snopes.com/">snopes</a>, <a href="http://rationalwiki.org/">RationalWiki</a> or <a href="http://skepdic.com/">The Skeptic&rsquo;s Dictionary</a>. Really, it just takes a few moments of your time and you might be blown away by the things you find.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It took me such a long time to come around to thinking critically, but when I did, it was exciting, it was as if I got <a href="http://static.squarespace.com/static/507dba43c4aabcfd2216a447/t/51a2302de4b0e2549bbe8028/1369583665476/photo%20(18).PNG">a new start</a> in life. It was invigorating, it was tough and it has been totally worth it. Ignorance is not an excuse, ignorance is not bliss.</p>

<p>For the most part of my life so far, I went along thinking that I had to be told what to believe, and took things at face value, but now I&rsquo;ve lerned to do my own research and adjust my thinking if I&rsquo;m wrong. It&rsquo;s made me a better person, though perhaps more vitriolic than before - that&rsquo;s a side effect of seeing people you care about sucked into believing ridiculous things.</p>

<p>Two things which are worth constantly remembering are:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/view/520156/memory-is-inherently-fallible-and-thats-a-good-thing/">Memory is fallible</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sciencebasedmedicine.org/the-role-of-anecdotes-in-science-based-medicine/">Anecdote is unreliable</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Older X is better</h2>

<p>Normally in one of the following forms:</p>

<ul>
<li>[Insert appliance/thing here] were made so much better before</li>
<li>Life was so much better X years ago</li>
<li>New technology X is ruining our lives / making us less social</li>
</ul>


<p>I want to briefly address them one by one:</p>

<h3>Quality of construction</h3>

<p>This is easy, and something my wife and I have discussed several times. The appliance manufacturers do not put in time bombs into your dishwasher, vacuum cleaner, PC, mobile phone or printer so they die just out of warranty&hellip;but there are several important points to be made:</p>

<p><em>Things are a lot cheaper now.</em> for example a brand new washing machine in 1970 would cost you <a href="http://www.gti.net/mocolib1/prices/1970.html">around US $130</a>, but your yearly (median household) income was <a href="http://www.davemanuel.com/median-household-income.php">around US $7600</a>. Now you can find a washing machine for <a href="http://www.homedepot.com/p/Maytag-Centennial-3-6-cu-ft-High-Efficiency-Top-Load-Washer-in-White-ENERGY-STAR-MVWC360AW/203667281">about US $400 or less</a> - but the 2012 median income is about <a href="http://www.davemanuel.com/median-household-income.php">about US $50,000</a>.
That means an average household can now buy over 2 washing machines per year for every 1 they could back in 1970! (0.8% of yearly income vs 1.71%).</p>

<p><em>Grandpa knew how to fix the washing machine.</em> It DID break down, but it was fixed at home. Some people can still do that, others can&rsquo;t.</p>

<p><em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias">Confirmation bias</a> &amp; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anecdotal_evidence">anecdote</a> reign supreme.</em> the articles / blogs I found saying &ldquo;modern&rdquo; things are worse were written without evidence, and were along the lines of &ldquo;my washing machine broke down after 10 years, I bought a new one and it died after 2.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s not evidence, at least not by itself&hellip;Do you know the manufacturer return rates then vs now? What about giving a product time to see how long it lasts, a 2 year old product logically can&rsquo;t have anyone using it for 10 years! Besides, <a href="http://aceee.org/research-report/a132">this isn&rsquo;t necessarily the truth</a>. Modern appliances function better and are more efficient, saving you money in more ways than one.</p>

<h3>The good ol&#8217; days</h3>

<p>Anyone who knows me has probably heard me rant about this more than once&hellip;</p>

<p>I won&rsquo;t go into great detail but.</p>

<p><em>Violent crime is down</em> see the following image of violent crime by gender per 1000 people: (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crime_in_the_United_States">via wikipedia</a>)
<img class="<a" src="href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/66/Violent_crime_rates_by_gender_1973-2003.jpg">http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/66/Violent_crime_rates_by_gender_1973-2003.jpg</a>&#8221; title=&#8221;&lsquo;Violent crime is down&rsquo; &lsquo;Wikipedia Image showing violent crime per 1000&rsquo;&#8221; ></p>

<p><em>Life expectancy is up!</em> If you were lucky enough to be born in the 1850s you would have a <a href="http://www.infoplease.com/ipa/A0005140.html">lovely life expectancy</a> of <strong>38.3</strong>* years. If you were born in 2004, that age now becomes <strong>75.7!</strong> Going further back in time than 1850, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Life_expectancy">things are just as grim</a>.</p>

<h3>Kids these days / AKA the good ol&#8217; days part 2</h3>

<p>Something oft repeated&hellip;&ldquo;this generation is worse.&rdquo; &ldquo;Technology is driving us apart.&rdquo;</p>

<p>As always. There&rsquo;s a <a href="http://xkcd.com/1227/">relevant XKCD</a> which nicely illustrates how people have been saying the same things for a long time!</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s an excerpt from a 1908 essay on ancient Greek Schools entitled <a href="http://www.archive.org/stream/schoolsofhellasa008878mbp#page/n105/mode/2up/search/indictment">&ldquo;Schools of Hella - An Essay On The Practice And Theory Of Ancient Greek Education From 600 To 300 BC&rdquo;</a> by Kenneth J. Freeman.</p>

<p><img src="/images/schoolsofhellas.jpg" /></p>

<blockquote><p>The counts of indictment are luxury, bad manners, contempt for authority, disrespect to elders, and a love for chatter in place of exercise.</p></blockquote>

<p>&hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p>Children began to be the tyrants, not the slaves of their households. They no longer rose from their seats when an elder entered the room ; they contradicted their parents, chattered before company, gobbled up the dainties at the table, and committed various offences against Hellenic tastes, such as crossing their legs.</p></blockquote>

<p>Kids these days are getting out of control.</p>

<p>People are afraid of change, time after time we see the same issues come up as long as you can go back. I hate it now that horses are domesticated, people are leaving their villages and families and it&rsquo;s tearing society apart!</p>

<h2>Anyone who does X is stupid</h2>

<p>While there are <a href="http://www.darwinawards.com/">many exceptions</a> to this, the attitude of putting people into baskets is so detrimental. It means before you even get a chance to understand their reasoning, you&rsquo;ve already judged them and even if you are wrong, you still experience <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias">confirmation bias</a>.</p>

<p>Example: All goth kids are depressed.</p>

<ul>
<li>JP: Hi Goth Kid</li>
<li>GK: Hi Judgmental Person</li>
<li>JP: How&rsquo;s it going?</li>
<li>GK: good thanks, it&rsquo;s a great day today but I&rsquo;m not looking forward to going to work tomorrow</li>
<li>JP: I knew it, you have such a bleary outlook on life</li>
<li>GK: Oh, so you&rsquo;re looking forward to work then?</li>
<li>JP: No, but&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>Next time you tell a story think, why are you mentioning the race of the person or their sexual orientation as part of the story (unless it&rsquo;s strictly relevant). I don&rsquo;t often hear stories about this Australian driver (unless you&rsquo;re overseas and then you can hear the Aussie jokes&hellip;), or this straight guy. You&rsquo;re leading the listener on with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loaded_language">loaded language</a> and reinforcing stereotypes, even if it&rsquo;s unintentional.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>This turned out longer than I expected, but there is so much material to cover and I feel like I haven&rsquo;t done it justice. I would love to discuss this more and I have some ideas for the content of my next post.</p>

<p><strong>Just think!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
