<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | zeyus dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-12T14:03:22+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.zeyus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[zeyus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter to My Family]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2015/02/26/an-open-letter-to-my-family/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T12:35:14+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2015/02/26/an-open-letter-to-my-family</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Mum, dad and Leah,</p>

<p>Firstly, I want to say that I care about you and I&rsquo;d always assumed that you would be a part of my life. Sadly this is no longer the case, and I can&rsquo;t see it changing, ever.</p>

<p>I tried to make it as clear as possible - to no effect - that I wasn&rsquo;t taking a step against you by leaving the Jehovah&rsquo;s Witnesses, I disagree with their teachings, the way they enforce their beliefs, and how insulated they are from reality. That has nothing to do with how I feel about you.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the doctrines you have put all your effort into believing, make you cut me off, for essentially what boils down to a disagreement in beliefs. So what? I&rsquo;m still the same person I was 2 months ago, 2 years ago, 20 years ago. I haven&rsquo;t killed anyone, I haven&rsquo;t abused you, I haven&rsquo;t done anything worthy of being kicked out of the family.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s kind of funny that originally the JWs were so critical of the catholic practice of ex-communication, saying that it&rsquo;s unbiblical (citing scriptural proof), yet now they do the same, except it&rsquo;s even worse, because the JWs make it to be a complete exile from family and friends (and cite scriptural proof for it). See image:</p>

<p><img src="/images/xc.jpg" alt="excommunication denounced by jehovah's witnesses" /></p>

<p>It just blows me away that you&rsquo;re so wrapped up in this cult you can&rsquo;t see what you&rsquo;re actually doing.</p>

<p><em>You abandoned your own son/brother over a disagreement in belief</em></p>

<p><strong>You abandoned your own son/brother over a disagreement in belief</strong></p>

<p><strong><em>You abandoned your own son/brother over a disagreement in belief</em></strong></p>

<p>Does that seem reasonable? As a father, I can never ever imagine doing that, no matter what!</p>

<p>I wasn&rsquo;t angry before, even though you kept claiming it over and over. I&rsquo;m angry now, I&rsquo;m furious. I despise the Jehovah&rsquo;s Witnesses, but only slightly more than most other religions, so don&rsquo;t think your doctrines are that special or some prophecy is coming true, it&rsquo;s not.</p>

<p>I had some good times and bad times growing up. The good times I had were despite the church, not because of it. Sure I made friends from the congregation, but I had little choice in that. Those friends I had were good while it lasted and I enjoyed the times I spent with them eating, going out, surfing, riding motorcycles and everything else. I didn&rsquo;t enjoy sitting down for evenings, weekends, and other times stuck in a stuffy room listening to people drone on about a god of love who kills everyone. Is that really a surprise? Whatever, that&rsquo;s not the point of this letter anyway.</p>

<p>I know there&rsquo;s nothing I can say to change your mind, but the only thing I want to get across is this:</p>

<ul>
<li>You actively cut me off, while you have said explicitly that you think it&rsquo;s my fault, it isn&rsquo;t. I can choose what I believe based on evidence. You choose to cut me off because of this.</li>
<li>What you&rsquo;ve done is wrong, and frankly, disgusting</li>
<li>Please admit to yourself that you decided to delete me from your life because we disagree on beliefs and for no other reason, then think about that</li>
</ul>


<p>You are still able to see, and communicate with Kai and Erik, and even Andrea. You see no problem with doing so, as long as I&rsquo;m not around. It should be obvious at this point who took the step of breaking all the ties, it certainly wasn&rsquo;t me or my family.</p>

<p>I hope you are well, you wont be reading this so it doesn&rsquo;t matter anyway, but I love you.</p>

<p>Luke</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Story - Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2014/01/24/my-story-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-24T21:09:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2014/01/24/my-story-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> thought that now might be as good a time as any to write about about my life. As you can see, it&rsquo;s on my blog, it&rsquo;s not going to be a bestseller and I&rsquo;m doing it for me. If it so happens that you enjoy reading it, all the better!</p>

<p>Be warned: as far as I know there is no murder or CSI style investigations. Because I&rsquo;m not drafting, editing and proofing this, it might not be as coherent or polished as it should be. Some parts will be too light on detail, and others too heavy.</p>

<p>Part one is going to end when I&rsquo;ve written as much as I feel like tonight.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2> Pre history</h2>

<p>I was born in Penrith, a medium size city to the west of Sydney. My dad is an electrician, he has always worked hard and is most happy when he has a million things to do. My mum is a school teacher, she was born in Finland and came over when she was young. My parents went to the same school together.</p>

<p><img src="/images/young_mum.jpg" title="&lsquo;mum with mummu&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>My parents had travelled a lot around Australia, and in the case of my dad, the world. He spent about a year backpacking all over the place. I don&rsquo;t remember with certainty but it included Europe and India at least.</p>

<p><img src="/images/young_mum.jpg" title="&lsquo;young dad travelling&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>They tell me that they weren&rsquo;t particularly religious before the Jehovah&rsquo;s Witnesses came knocking at their door, and were seemingly skeptical about what the JWs were offering. I&rsquo;m not sure if they were called on at a vulnerable point in their lives, but for whatever reason, they started a bible study[*][#fn0001] with the witnesses.</p>

<p>Dad and mum were married on a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paddle_steamer">paddle steamer</a> on the Nepean River. It was a small affair with only close friends and family in attendance.</p>

<p>The first place I lived in was a 3 bedroom house in the foot of the blue mountains. I have fond memories of this place. It had a decent sized yard, a pool and a sauna (which is probably my most loved thing about the place - my dad built a sauna in the places we lived for my mum. It&rsquo;s very Finnish.) My grandmother (mummu) lived there too, but she had a granny flat above the garage which allowed her to be independent.</p>

<p>There are lots of photos of holidays I went on, long before I can remember, I have a few flashes here and there, but not many. I know we went yearly down to camp by the beach in southern New South Wales, we made fires, caught fish, swam and were surrounded by wildlife.</p>

<p><img src="/images/baby_me.jpg" width="400" height="400" title="&lsquo;baby Luke&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t remember my sister being born two years after me, as far as I remember she&rsquo;s always been there.</p>

<h2>First memories - school</h2>

<p>Actually, my memory from my whole youth is piecemeal and hopefully writing this dawn might help recall more. There are things I do remember though, like making a volcano with food dye, vinegar and baking soda, and before that a memory of burning my ass on a fireplace. I had to go to hospital for it, I don&rsquo;t remember that part, but I do remember the reason I was naked in front of the fireplace was because I&rsquo;d just bathed, and I wanted to get warm and dry, in doing so I guess I got a little closer than what you might call a safe distance. Lesson learned, I never did that again.</p>

<p>I remember my a few things from my first year and a bit of school. Once I got detention for kicking my shoes over the fence accidentally in a game my friends and I thought was hilarious. The game was such: loosen the lace on your shoe and lift the tongue up. Kick your leg forward as vigorously as possible, and see how far your shoe goes. Collect shoe. Repeat. Of course it was great fun up until the point where the shoe went soaring over the fence, and after being told off, we had to sheepishly knock on the neighbour&rsquo;s door and ask for the safe return of said footwear. Luckily (living next to a school) they were probably used to articles of clothing landing in their yard and helpfully returned my shoe. If I remember rightly, these shoes had a pump in the tongue which inflated it when pressed, they seemed to make me happy,</p>

<p>I had a little crew of friends that used to play soccer and roam the schoolyard together, I don&rsquo;t remember much of our conversations but they probably revolved around lunch, who&rsquo;s dad is better, and who we did and didn&rsquo;t like in class. I remember one classmate called Sarah with whom I was smitten and she would be the one I&rsquo;d always go after in &ldquo;Kiss and catch.&rdquo; Of course in a dancing lesson i remember, I hoped that I would be paired with her - instead, as there were more boys in my class, I got stuck with a redhead kid called Corey who had warts on his hands and wasn&rsquo;t thought of fondly by my gang.</p>

<p>At some point I wanted / was encouraged to learn an instrument, so I decided on the piano. Little did I know how seriously my parents would take this, forcing me to practice an hour a day and take exams and perform in eisteddfods and talent shows. Eeek, held to a decision you made when you&rsquo;re 4 or 5 for the next 8 years is pretty hardcore. (It was made far less fun for me because the music is chosen for you when you take the AMEB exams, usually classical music which my 4-27 year old self had/has very little interest in.)</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s not much else that stands out from there except I was bored in class, and the teachers had me sit a test and because I did so well they decided I should skip a year, and I think there was some &ldquo;gifted and talented&rdquo; class in there somewhere too. I think that was a mistake because I missed out on some fundamental education that meant I had to play catchup, and I suppose that&rsquo;s what lead to my incessant complaining of school. I asked my mum to teach me at home because she&rsquo;s a teacher - and she did.</p>

<p>So my school years ended abruptly and my new life at home began.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today and I guess I&rsquo;ll continue from where I left off here at some point.</p>

<p><a id="fn0001">* In JW terms &ldquo;bible study&rdquo; does not in fact mean studying the bible, but means studying one of their publications.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coming to Terms]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2014/01/15/coming-to-terms/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T11:54:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2014/01/15/coming-to-terms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The path that was</h2>

<p>Oh I never had very high expectations of what would become of my life. I was taught from the moment I can remember that this life was just a transient state, &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t invest too much in this life, prepare for the one to come!&rdquo; or &ldquo;&lsquo;The Truth&rsquo; [JW speak for the JW religion] isn&rsquo;t a religion, it&rsquo;s a way of life.&rdquo; or &ldquo;Satan roves about like a roaring lion waiting to devour&hellip;&rdquo; Constant quotes, pithy phrases and one-liners were thrown at me. Most of them with the outward intention of bolstering my faith but always with a more sinister message of spending even more time focusing on religion and sparing no time for other activities.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;ll probably go into a lot more detail on my upbringing in a future post, but for now the focus is on my current state of mind.</p>

<p>From when I was very young I had a love of science and technology. I got to read a lot but always through the blind eyes of faith. I read in awe books about our amazing planet and life on it, yet managed to ignore any reference to evolution (and anything else that went against my &ldquo;truth&rdquo;) and in doing so feel proud of myself that I had the right answer, all the scientists were wrong. They were just too smart to see the simplistic beauty that was a divine creator, if only they would pick up their bibles. Ugh, I sucked.</p>

<p>It took an exceptionally long time to clear out everything that had been forced into my mind from years of spoon fed, watered down misinformation - I had to start from zero. A humbling experience, finding out that almost every single thing you thought you knew and believed to the core was wrong. I had to question everything, I researched minute detail, I read lots (and will continue to do so) on science and critical thinking.</p>

<p>Between those two stages, I was left seemingly without purpose. I didn&rsquo;t mind though, I adopted a somewhat hedonistic approach to life, self destructive perhaps. I worked, I did my part, but amidst that was a bunch of excesses that weren&rsquo;t easy to curb.</p>

<p>Somewhere around that time I met my amazing wife and we were soon smitten with each other, luckily for us we even out each other&rsquo;s extremes in just the right way. Her presence, constant support, intelligence and enthusiasm kept me learning new things and examining the status quo.</p>

<h2>The now</h2>

<p>Thanks in a exceptionally large part to her, I am where I am today. In a happy relationship with 2 beautiful kids, living in a nice area of a great city with a good job. Many people would be envious, some scornful, though I never thought I based my decisions on what would bring me the most accolade from others. By many measures of life, and despite my upbringing I have achieved success, and yet it doesn’t feel like it.</p>

<p>Andrea and I talked about this and she asked what it would take to bring about that feeling. I honestly do not know. It&rsquo;s not about not being content with what I have - I am, very much so. I appreciate how well things are for me I love nearly every aspect of my life. Partly it stems from a desire to leave a lasting contribution, something that matters, maybe something that would make up for all my wasted time and even poisonous input into society. (You probably didn&rsquo;t think twice about it, but sorry if I ever knocked on your door and tried to scare you into thinking that the world is horrible and you need saving.)</p>

<p>The result of this melancholic state was that (with some nudging) I have done some thinking and written this blog post almost as a fluid thought process. Andrea pointed out that I have more time now to pursue my interests, I no longer have the option of squandering my time on activities that I used to like going out several nights every week. Basically the hours between 19:00-22:00 are mine, I&rsquo;m not going to make the best use of every minute, and my wife and kids will always come first, but I can force myself to make at least some nights count!</p>

<h2>The path that may be</h2>

<p><img src="/images/wtf.png" width="400" height="400" title="jump" ></p>

<p>So what can I contribute? What am I passionate about? I have no idea, really, so as a beginning I&rsquo;ve compiled a list of things that I want to do. This is not a new year&rsquo;s resolution, it&rsquo;s not a to do or a bucket list. It&rsquo;s just a vague list, but I will do some of these things, some I&rsquo;ve even started. Others could turn into goals - both long and short term. Some things may be added and others struck off. It is a start, a first step in the right direction, a slight narrowing of a broad cacophony of sentiments and ideas.</p>

<ul>
<li>Write, AND FINISH a song</li>
<li>Sing that song or another one to Andrea</li>
<li>Write a story (length and genre not specified) and submit it somewhere</li>
<li>Write an (mobile or desktop) application</li>
<li>Own a successful business (in what? define success?)</li>
<li>Learn another programming language</li>
<li>Speak Spanish at home</li>
<li>Learn a third spoken language</li>
<li>Plan more</li>
<li>Write more in this blog</li>
<li>Live in another country</li>
<li>Buy a house</li>
<li>Grow a nice edible garden</li>
<li>Read more</li>
<li>Go to university (not just work at one. hah)</li>
<li>Help educate people (specifically in critical thinking)</li>
<li>Fight misinformation</li>
<li>Attend a conference (TED maybe?)</li>
<li>&hellip;?</li>
</ul>


<p>That&rsquo;s it for now. I will keep track of new things I think of or other things I remember and add them here.</p>

<p>Just getting to this point has been a good thing, and setting some long term goals, defining them and keeping them in mind requires an attitude shift and lots of thought. I have a bad track record when it comes to that, but then again, I know nothing&hellip;but I&rsquo;m willing to learn!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
