<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Entertainment | zeyus dot com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/categories/entertainment/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-26T13:13:04+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.zeyus.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[zeyus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 10 TV Shows That I've Probably Told You About 100 Times]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2014/03/12/top-10-tv-shows-that-ive-probably-told-you-about-100-times/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T20:50:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.zeyus.com/blog/2014/03/12/top-10-tv-shows-that-ive-probably-told-you-about-100-times</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A fun post because I&rsquo;m too tired to go into anything meaty, and I thought I should update my blog once in a while&hellip;I have a few things to write about, and to continue my story but it will have to wait till another day.</p>

<p>I wont give them ratings, and I wont iterate that you should watch them if you haven&rsquo;t, otherwise they wouldn&rsquo;t be on this list. I&rsquo;ve not really reviewed things before, which means I might not sell the show to you as well as I should, but just assume they&rsquo;re better than I describe them. So without further ado, the list in all its glory:</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>10. Extras</h2>

<p><img src="/images/extras.jpg" title="&lsquo;Extras&rsquo; &lsquo;Extras&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Ricky Gervais is one of the masters of awkward comedy, and Extras is very well done. Each episode starring a different guest, including the likes of Daniel Radcliff (in which he manages to get a condom land in someone&rsquo;s hair), Patrick Stewart and Samuel L Jackson. Even when landing his own comedy show Andy Millman (Gervais) just doesn&rsquo;t seem to have things going well for him. His useless manager Darren (Stephen Merchant) is also hilarious in his role.</p>

<h2>9. South Park</h2>

<p><img src="/images/south_park.jpg" title="&lsquo;South Park&rsquo; &lsquo;South Park&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure there&rsquo;s anyone who hasn&rsquo;t seen at least one episode of South Park, a lot of people can&rsquo;t stand it, Andrea falls asleep when South Park comes on. Personally I love it. Matt and Trey have consistently created good content, leaving nothing sacred. It&rsquo;s crude, it&rsquo;s on point and I there hasn&rsquo;t been many (if any) episodes that I haven&rsquo;t had a good laugh at. One of the things I love about the show is how it comments on current events and pop culture and just takes it to the absurd.</p>

<h2>8. Curb Your Enthusiasm</h2>

<p><img src="/images/curb.jpg" title="&lsquo;Curb Your Enthusiasm&rsquo; &lsquo;Curb Your Enthusiasm&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Perhaps you liked Seinfeld, I know I did, it&rsquo;s one of my favourite shows even though it didn&rsquo;t make the cut for the top 10. Regardless, Larry David clearly was the driving force behind the show. In Curb, he plays a likeable asshole, who you have to admit is right more than he is wrong, but he manages to piss everyone off with every move he makes. Sometimes you feel sorry for him, sometimes you hide behind a pillow while Larry goes and does something you know you&rsquo;d love to in real life but don&rsquo;t have the balls to.</p>

<h2>7. Louie</h2>

<p><img src="/images/louie.jpg" title="&lsquo;Louie&rsquo; &lsquo;Louie&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Louie CK is a comedic genius. His show is based around his life, which he makes seem extremely mundane and boring, but yet his interactions with his friends, family and acquaintances are incredibly well done and always get a laugh. I think he balances the comedy with moments of feeling and tackles some more serious issues, then proceeds to piss on them. Also love the great stand up segments which may remind you of Seinfeld, though 1000x better.</p>

<h2>6. Freaks and Geeks</h2>

<p><img src="/images/freaks_and_geeks.jpg" title="&lsquo;Freaks and Geeks&rsquo; &lsquo;Freaks and Geeks&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Focused on the life of two siblings Lindsay (Linda Cardellini) and Sam (John Francis Daley) in high school. Freaks and Geeks is both funny and manages to address what it&rsquo;s like trying to fit in and some of the issues you face growing up. I watched this only a few years ago and from the first episode was hooked. I&rsquo;m not sure how I would have felt watching it as a teen considering I was in a totally different place. It was jus really enjoyable. Oh, and it&rsquo;s only 1 season (18 episodes), so you&rsquo;ll be left wanting more, but obviously the show never had the chance to get tired and played out.</p>

<h2>5. Borgen</h2>

<p><img src="/images/borgen.jpg" title="&lsquo;Borgen&rsquo; &lsquo;Borgen&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>OK, we are still in the process of watching this show, and hopefully it wont end up being really disappointing, but we&rsquo;ve almost finished season 2 and it&rsquo;s been excellent! This show revolves around Birgitte, a career politician who is very idealistic, and wants to bring about change in the Danish government. It&rsquo;s an fascinating look into the life of a politician and the drama that surrounds even the minutiae of a public figure&rsquo;s personal life. There are moments of intense atmosphere that builds and builds, and the acting is superb.</p>

<h2>4. Breaking Bad</h2>

<p><img src="/images/breaking_bad.jpg" title="&lsquo;Breaking Bad&rsquo; &lsquo;Breaking Bad&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Well, no doubt you&rsquo;ve heard about this show, and most likely watched it. If you&rsquo;ve been putting it off, then now&rsquo;s the time to start. Walter White (Bryan Cranston) is a school teacher who finds out some bad news and decides the best way to spend the rest of his days is to make a buttload of cash making meth. Of course, it&rsquo;s not that simple, and the show has some explosive moments. I&rsquo;d say it&rsquo;s a lot more drama than action, which is fine. The show is just so well done, from the acting, to the cinematography (which to me seems like they have thought out every detail of every shot) and the dialogue. There are scenes when no words are said but the atmosphere is ripe and leaves you squeezing your chair.</p>

<h2>3. Game of Thrones</h2>

<p><img src="/images/game_of_thrones.jpg" title="&lsquo;Game of Thrones&rsquo; &lsquo;Game of Thrones&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Well, there&rsquo;s not much more you can ask for in a series, there&rsquo;s action, there&rsquo;s intrigue, there&rsquo;s murder, there are fantastic creatures and there&rsquo;s naked people&hellip;yep it&rsquo;s all covered. I hadn&rsquo;t read the books before I started watching the show, and the first season came as a bit of a shock to me. I&rsquo;ve since read all bar the last half of the latest book. Honestly the show is way better than the books. George R R Martin is a bit hit and miss with his descriptions seemingly happy to spend 84 pages describing the bark of a tree whereas the show basically cuts a lot of the cruft away and manages to be extremely entertaining and leaves you wanting more, but not in the shitty Lost way where nothing happens, but in a really good way where you enjoy it and you know you&rsquo;ll enjoy the next one, even if the events in the show weren&rsquo;t what you would like to happen.</p>

<h2>2. Forbrydelsen</h2>

<p><img src="/images/forbrydelsen.jpg" title="&lsquo;Forbrydelsen&rsquo; &lsquo;Forbrydelsen&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Surprise surprise, another Danish show on the list. Well it just so happens that Forbrydelsen is about as perfect as any show can get. It&rsquo;s a police murder mystery type show with only 3 seasons, and each season being a different case. Sara Lund (Sofie Gråbøl) is a police officer who is really great at what she does, she loves it so much she lets her personal life slide. As you watch, at times you&rsquo;re both in admiration and completely frustrated with her. Sofie is an amazing actress. The story is brilliant, and even if you can work out who the baddies are (like Andrea did hah) you will want to watch it. The Danes shure know how to make some good TV.</p>

<h2>1. House of Cards (2013)</h2>

<p><img src="/images/house_of_cards.jpg" title="&lsquo;House of Cards&rsquo; &lsquo;House of Cards&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>This show absolutely smashed it&rsquo;s way to the top of my list, it&rsquo;s just that good. Francis Underwood (Kevin Spacey) is a ruthless (psychopathic) politician who is social engineering his way to the top. The dialogue is classy, the SE techniques he uses are spot on, and the entire cast do a great job in their roles. His wife Claire (Robin Wright) is just as devious as Frank is and watching the details of their relationship become revealed is intriguing. It&rsquo;s a reflection on the current state of politics and how little faith people have in politicians. If Borgen shows an idealistic view of democracy, House of Cards is the take from the seedy underbelly. It is fucking awesome!</p>

<h1>Honorable Mentions</h1>

<ul>
<li>House</li>
<li>Sarah Silverman Show</li>
<li>Spaced</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia</li>
</ul>


<p>And that&rsquo;s it, hope you enjoyed my list!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
